<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Armin Sobhani</title><link>https://arminms.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Armin Sobhani</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 16:04:07 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arminms.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automating Software Build Process using CMake - Part I</title><link>https://arminms.github.io/posts/videos/cmake_1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 16:04:07 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://arminms.github.io/posts/videos/cmake_1/</guid><description>This webinar was presented by me on September 14, 2016 as a part of a series of regular biweekly webinars ran by SHARCNET. CMake is a cross-platform, free and open-source build system that allows you automatically build, test, verify, package and deploy software in a compiler-independent manner. CMake was originally created in 1999 for the Insight Toolkit (ITK) funded by the US National Library of Medicine (NLM) as part of the Visible Human Project and over the past 17 years has become the most popular build tool for C/C++ especially in the field of scientific research (e.</description></item><item><title>Programming with Wt - A C++ library for developing stateful and highly interactive web applications</title><link>https://arminms.github.io/posts/videos/wt/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 16:04:07 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://arminms.github.io/posts/videos/wt/</guid><description>This webinar was presented by me on June 24th, 2015 as a part of a series of regular biweekly webinars ran by SHARCNET. If you need to expose a new HPC service or a brand new scientific methodology to outside community by developing a highly interactive web application but without gaining familiarity with ever-changing technologies such as HTML/XHTML, JavaScript, CSS, AJAX, CGI, DHTML, SVG/VML/Canvas, PHP, etc., this webinar is for you.</description></item></channel></rss>